Joshua Langer

3335 93rd Curve Blaine, MN 55449 (612) 723-4971 joshuarllanger@gmail.com GitHub - LinkedIn - Twitter github.com/JoshuaLanger linkedin.com/in/josh-r-langer twitter.com/joshrlanger

SUMMARY

Front-end web developer skilled in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, and Git. Experienced in developing and designing websites and applications using both front-end and back-end technologies. Persistent, resourceful, and punctual creator who works well alone and with a team.

SKILLS

HTML5 React Issue Resolution Client Relationship
CSS3 Git Knowledge and Resource Management
JavaScript (ES6) UI/UX Design Procurement Team Collaboration

PROJECTS

Quick Draw! (quick-draw.app)

July 2018

- A game that tests reflexes and returns a total score.
- Built with the React framework and styled-components library.

Virtual Reality Simulation

Feb 2016 - May 2016

- Collaborated with other students to develop simulation for doctors-in-training to examine and diagnose a virtual patient afflicted with stroke.
- Utilized Unity, Blender, and MakeHuman software to allow user to interact with virtual patient in a realistic and credible way.

Student Registration System

Feb 2015 – May 2015

- Worked on team to design, develop, and execute student registration system.
- Planned process and development regularly to track progress.

EXPERIENCE

Client Support Representative

April 2018 – January 2019

Target, Brooklyn Park, MN

- Resolves technical and procedural issues for Target employees, prioritizing a speedy recovery in under 5 minutes to improve productivity.
- Contributes to knowledge base and trends in weekly peer meetings.

Computer Lab Technician

March 2017—January 2018

Anoka-Ramsey Community College, Coon Rapids, MN

- Solved technical issues at IT help desk and over phone from students and faculty.
- Worked as part of a team to coordinate deliveries or resolve issues.

EDUCATION

University of Minnesota

Graduated 2016

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

- Studied several concepts such as web development, software development, algorithms, object-oriented design, and UI/UX design.
- Developed several programs on own and with a team.